politics.ie 2010-05-01

# Politics.ie - The Irish Politics Website - Privacy Policy

Politics.ie Privacy Statement

Revised: _December 2009  _

**Introduction  **

This privacy statement sets out how Politics.ie (the website) collects, uses and protects any information you give us when you use Politics.ie.

We are committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. Should you give us any information by which you can be identified when using Politics.ie then you can be assured that we will use it only in accordance with this privacy statement. 

We may change this policy from time to time. If we do we will notify you of such changes by a site-wide announcement. This will be visible on all forum pages for one week from the date of the changes. After that, you can continue to find from a link at the bottom of each page on Politics.ie. Your continued use of Politics.ie constitutes a binding acceptance of this policy. 

**Children under the age of 13  **

Politics.ie is not directed at children younger than 13 years of age and is offered only to users who are 13 or older. Children below 13 may not register with Politics.ie. We do not knowingly collect information from or about children below the age of 13. If we discover that we have collected personal information from a child below the age of 13 we will delete that information as soon as possible. If you believe we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us at info@politics.ie. 

**Persons aged 13 to 17  **

We recommend that young people aged 13 years of age or older ask their parents or legal guardians for permission before using Politics.ie or sending any information about themselves to anyone over the Internet. 

**What we collect**  

We collect the following information: 

  * Information which you supply on registration or as part of your profile;
  * Information which you provide in relation to any payment;
  * Information which you post on Politics.ie;
  * Information which you otherwise provide to us (for example by email or private message); and
  * Information relating to your use of Politics.ie generally. This includes, for example, private messages, login and logout times, polls you’ve voted on, threads to which you have subscribed and posts you’ve thanked.

 Technical details in connection with visits to this website are logged by our internet service provider for our statistical purposes. The technical details logged include: 

  * The IP address of a visitor and the top-level domain name used (for example .ie, .com, .org, .net);
  * The previous website address from which a visitor reached us, including any search terms used;
  * “Clickstream” data which shows the traffic of visitors around Politics.ie (for example pages accessed and documents downloaded); and
  * the type of web browser used by a visitor.

No information is collected that could be used by us to identify website visitors and we will not attempt to associate these technical details with any individual. This technical information will be used only by Politics.ie and only for statistical and other administrative purposes. 

In common with many sites we use outside providers for web-site statistics. Please note that to provide statistics these use visitors’ IP addresses but do not have access to any Politics.ie usernames or email address. The providers we use are Google Analytics. You can find further information on Google Analytics [here](http://www.google.com/analytics/).

**Cookies  **

Politics.ie only uses cookies for temporary sessions which enable a visitor’s web browser to remember which pages on this website have already been visited. You should be able to use Politics.ie with no loss of functionality if cookies are disabled from the web browser. 

**External providers**  

From time to time we may ask an external provider to provide services, for example we may ask an external company to carry out a survey. If any personal information is required you will be advised beforehand. 

**What we do with the information we collect  **

We require this information for the operation of Politics.ie, to understand your needs and provide you with a better service. In particular, we may use or disclose your information for the following reasons: 

  * We may use this information for our administration, record keeping and in connection with any payment;
  * We may use this information for technical processing and to address technical problems or service complaints;
  * We may disclose this information where required by law to do so;
  * We may disclose this information to law enforcement, government officials or courts where we believe that disclosure is necessary and proportionate; and
  * We may disclose this information where we believe that disclosure is necessary and proportionate for the protection of the legitimate interests of ourselves or of a third party.

 We will not otherwise disclose, sell or distribute your information to any third party without your permission. 

**Anonymous and aggregated data  **

We may aggregate data in an anonymous manner for disclosure to advertisers or business associates for promotion and marketing purposes. By way of example, we may disclose to an advertiser the number of unique visitors to Politics.ie or the percentage age groups of our members. In such an event we undertake to ensure that no such data could be used to personally identify you. 

**Nuisance posts  **

Our first line of defence against nuisance posts is to delete them and to ban the user. Nuisance posts include potentially defamatory material, surreptitious advertising, any other posts which breach the posting guidelines and any form of messages, posts or emails deemed offensive by the administrators or moderators. 

Where a nuisance poster persists, we reserve the right to use email addresses and IP addresses to identify the user and halt the nuisance. 

For example, on a very few occasions, we have reported to organisations that it appeared that one of their employees or other users of their computer equipment was repeatedly making nuisance posts on Politics.ie and asked them to take steps to stop it. 

Due to persistent and deliberate trolling and attacks on Politics.ie, we've suspended registration of new members of Politics.ie until further notice.

**Information you post  **

Any personal information which you volunteer in your public profile or post on the forums will be available worldwide to anyone with access to the website. 

Please do not post any information you are not happy to leave up indefinitely. We recommend you do not post your name, address, telephone number email address or anything else that may lead someone to identify you if this is something you are uncomfortable with. Please note that we do not delete posts on request, except in special circumstances. 

Please note that certain information (such as photographs) which you may choose to provide might reveal your gender, ethnic origin, nationality, religion and/or sexual orientation. 

**Anonymous / pseudonymous users  **

You are free (if you wish) to choose a username which does not reflect your real name. Occasionally users may speculate about the identity of anonymous or pseudonymous users. Such speculation is rarely tolerated and we delete all such posts which are brought to our attention. However please be aware that we cannot guarantee that other users will not be able to determine your identity. 

**User status  **

Please note that your user status will appear in connection with your username. This may be derived by your post count, your membership, or another title at the discretion of the Administrators of Politics.ie. If you become banned from using Politics.ie, the word "Banned" may appear under your username. Similarly, should you receive a warning relating to your use of Politics.ie, a yellow card may appear. 

**Controlling your personal information  **

You may request details of personal information which we hold about you or rectify any personal information which is incorrect or incomplete under the Data Protection Acts 1988-2003. 

If you would like a copy of the information held on you please email us at [info@politics.ie](mailto:info@politics.ie). If you are a registered user please supply details of your username and email address which you supplied when registering. Please note that to protect your privacy we may require further information to verify your identity. 

If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please email us as soon as possible at [info@politics.ie](mailto:info@politics.ie). We will promptly correct any information found to be incorrect. 

If someone else has posted material about you on Politics.ie without your permission and you would like it removed please contact us at [info@politics.ie](mailto:info@politics.ie). If you can provide the URL (page address) to direct our attention along with your email, this will help Politics.ie address this in a prompt fashion. 

**Security  **

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

Our most recent comprehensive security audit by an external consultant was completed on **December 21st 2009**.  
  
All times are GMT +1. The time now is 02:43 AM.
